Guide to the David McAllester Papers, 1940 - 1996
David McAllester Papers, 1940 - 1996
- Series IV: Personal History, 1941-1996
  - Non Compos Mentis, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Manuscript by patient at CT State Hospital.
  - Creative Patient, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Writings by patients for in house newspaper.
  - CT State Hospital, 1943-44 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Writings by patients.
  - Miscellaneous, bulk 1940s (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Drawings, partial letters, clippings.
  - Special treasures, 1952, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Guggenheim fellowship application, misc. photos, etc.
  - Monterey resources, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Natural Resource Inventory and Land Use Plan for Monterey, Massachusetts.
  - Celebrating David, 1982, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Exhibit: Navajo Art. Retirement events.
  - Mosquitoes, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Information on Eastern encephalitis.
  - Socially responsible investments, 1985-94 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    General information on topic.
  - Advisory board, 1986-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Monterey News.
  - Never Again Campaign, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Japanese program promoting peace and cultural understanding.
- Series V: Susan McAllester, 1944-1994
  Susan and David McAllester were married for over 50 years. This series contains letters written by Susan to David and also correspondence with her own friends. Some of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The rest of the correspondence is chronological. This is the way the Folders were originally created.
  - "Letters from Susan while she's laid up with lung", 1944 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Susan, 1944-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Susan, 1970-75 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Susan, 1976-79 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Susan, 1980-84 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Susan, 1985-89 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Susan, 1990-94 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondents, A-P (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondents, R-Z (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Pancreatic cancer, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Photo Album, c1894
  The single photograpah album in series VI is from the Park family of David McAllester's mother. Some of the photographs are labelled, but not all. Most of the photographs are tintypes.
  - Photographs of the family of Maude Helen Park (McAllester) (Box 20)